# estor D. Pereira Neto

Street Eduardo Campos nº 10, Boca do Rio, Salvador - BA, Brazil, 41705-230

"I have a degree in Electronic Engineering (2013) and a specialization in Biomedical Engineering (2019). I have experience in the maintenance of diagnostic imaging hospital equipment. In 2011, I started to work as a teacher in technical and higher education courses. I am currently finishing my Masters in Electrical Engineering at the Federal University of Bahia in the area of computing and robotics. Since 2019 I have had the pleasure of working in research and development in the field of robotics. Main areas of interest: Hardware development; Embedded systems; Real-time systems and robot perception."

### **Education**

#### Federal University of Bahia - UFBA

Salvador BA

MASTER'S DEGREE IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING - RESEARCH LINE: COMPUTING AND ROBOTICS

Apr. 2018 - Mar. 2022

• Communication between Robot Operating System - ROS and SoC with integrated FPGA.

Estácio de Sá University

Salvador, BA

SPECIALIZATION IN BIOMEDICAL ENGINEERING

Oct. 2017 - Feb. 2019

Convolutional Neural Network for Detection of QRS Complexes in Electrocardiogram Signals

#### Faculty of Science and Technology - ÁREA1

Salvador, BA

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN ELECTRONIC ENGINEERING

Feb. 2008 - Jul. 2013

- Command prototype to fit X-ray equipment to the standards required by the National Health Surveillance Agency ANVISA.
- Undergraduate research scholarship for two years

# **Experiências Profissionais**

**SENAI - CIMATEC** Salvador, BA

CONSULTANT II - ROBOTIC ENGINEERING

Apr. 2019 - currently

- ROS robotics framework: Gazebo Simulation, URDF/Xacro, SLAM Techniques.
- Programming python e C/C++.
- · Hardware and software integration.
- Hardware and firmware development for embedded systems.

PROFESSOR PART TIME - 20H Nov. 2018 - Apr. 2019

- · Teach class for the course: Industrial Mechatronics.
- Subjects: Analog Electronics and Digital Eletronic.

Salvador, BA

TÉCNICO DE LABORATÓRIO

Faculdade ÁREA1|Wyden

Jul. 2013 - Ago. 2017

- · Prepare and teach practical classes for the courses: Computer Engineering, Electrical Engineering and Automation Engineering.
- · Test new tools used in laboratories and provide training.
- Provide extension courses and the experience program.

Alfamed Fletromedicina Salvador, BA

Engenheiro - Responsável técnico

Ago. 2013 - Fev. 2015

- Technical responsible for the company.
- · Electronic maintenance in hospital bio-imaging equipment.

#### Centro Territorial de Educação Profissional da Região Metropolitana CETEP-RM

Camaçari, BA jun. 2011 - jun. 2013

PROFESSOR - 40H

• Ministrar aula das disciplinas: Eletrônica analógica e digital; Microcontroladores; Circuitos elétricos.

• Orientar alunos em seus trabalhos de conclusão de curso.

#### Micro Comércio e Serviço Ltda.

Salvador, BA

TÉCNICO DE MANUTENÇÃO

Jun. 2009 - Set. 2010

Manutenção preventiva e corretiva em equipamentos hospitalares de bioimagem.

ESTAGIÁRIO - MANUTENÇÃO

Mar. 2008 - Jun. 2009

• Manutenção preventiva e corretiva em equipamentos hospitalares de bioimagem.

# Idiomas

Português Nativo.

**Inglês** Nível intermediário.

#### Cursos

2018	NucLi - Inglês. Compreensão horal (32h), Universidade Federal da Bahia - UFBA	Salvador, BA
2010	Estudo do Controle de Dispositivos via portas paralela, serial e USB (60h), Faculdade ÁREA1.	Salvador, BA
2010	Eletrônica Analógica Aplicada (30h), Faculdade ÁREA1.	Salvador, BA

Treinamento em Tecnologia FPGA INTEL (20h), Macnica DHW - Centro Oficial de Treinamento FPGA INTEL

## **Projetos e Pesquisa**

SENAI CIMATEC Salvador, BA

SUBOT - CTG BRASIL

- Projeto de desenvolvimento de robótica móvel para inspeção de subestações de alta tensão.
- Desenvolvimento de hardware e firmware para sistemas atuadores e comunicação de periféricos.
- Desenvolvimento de ROS nodes em linguagem C/C++ e Python.
- Dimensionamento de sistema de compatibilidade eletromagnética do protótipo.

DIGISUB - PETROBRAS

Abr. 2019 - Out. 2021

- Projeto de desenvolvimento de digitalizador 3D de superfícies subaquáticas em águas profundas.
- Desenvolvimento de hardware e firmware para sistemas atuadores e comunicação de periféricos.
- Desenvolvimento de ROS nodes em linguagem C/C++ e Python.
- Dimensionamento de sistema de potência do protótipo: fontes, conversores AC-DC/DC-DC, baterias.

#### Escola Politécnica da Universidade Federal da Bahia - UFBA

Salvador, BA

Dez. 2018 - atualmente

Florianópolis, SC

Out. 2021 - Atualmente

Projeto de Mestrado

- Desenvolvimento comunicação 1 GigE entre FPGA e ROS.
- Projeto de hardware em verilog para implementação em SOC/FPGA (Cyclone V Intel).
- Programação socket em linguagem C/C++ para linux.
- Desenvolvimento de ROS nodes em linguagem C/C++.
- Trabalho apresentado no IBERCHIP 2022.

Faculdade ÁREA1 Salvador, BA

Iniciação Científica

Jul. 2011 - Jul. 2013

- Desenvolvimento de um comando microcontrolado para enquadrar equipamentos de raios X antigos às normas técnicas atuais.
- Programação de microcontroladores da família 8051 em linguagem assembly.
- Pesquisa das normas técnicas estabelecidas pela ANVISA em relação a equipamentos de raios X.
- Apresentação de relatórios mensais com as atividades desenvolvidas no período.
- Publicação dos resultados em artigo na revista Cientefico ISSN 1677-1591, jul/dez 2013.

# Competências e Habilidades

**Básico** Verilog HDL, Sockets, Cmake, GDB, Nios II, FreeRTOS, Linux embarcado, SimuLink.

**Intermediário** Python, ARM Cortex M, Linux, Git/Github, PIC, AutoCAD, ROS/Gazebo.

**Avançado** Layout de circuito impresso/KiCad, Matlab, C/C++, AVR, 8051, GNU-Make, LaTeX.